<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Sharing on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/book-sharing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Sharing on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/book-sharing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book Sharing|The Future Is in Your Hands</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/07/07/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/07/07/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/future.jpg&#34; width=&#34;360&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;The Future Is in Your Hands: Portrait Photography from Senegal&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview-of-the-book&#34;&gt;Overview of the Book&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Future Is in Your Hands: Portrait Photography from Senegal&lt;/em&gt; is a 2023 scholarly monograph by &lt;strong&gt;Beth A. Buggenhagen&lt;/strong&gt;, an anthropologist and Associate Professor at Indiana University Bloomington. Published by Indiana University Press as part of the Material Vernaculars series (edited by Jason Baird Jackson), the book explores the social, cultural, and material history of portrait photography in Senegal from colonial times through independence to contemporary practices. Buggenhagen draws on ethnographic fieldwork, archival research (including collections at the Smithsonian and in Senegal), and analysis of circulating images to examine how portraits embody themes of migration, family, identity, visibility, separation, rupture, and repatriation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Sharing|Why Gender Matters in Migration: Insights on Human Insecurity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/03/01/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/03/01/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Migration.jpg&#34; width=&#34;360&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Migration, Gender and Social Justice: Perspectives on Human Insecurity&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Migration, Gender and Social Justice: Perspectives on Human Insecurity&lt;/em&gt; is a 2014 open-access book published by Springer as part of the Hexagon Series on Human and Environmental Security and Peace (Vol. 9). Edited by Thanh-Dam Truong, Des Gasper, Jeff Handmaker, and Sylvia I. Bergh, all affiliated with the International Institute of Social Studies (ISS) at Erasmus University Rotterdam, it draws on multidisciplinary research from Africa, Asia, Europe, and Latin America. The book synthesizes findings from the International Development Research Centre&amp;rsquo;s (IDRC) Women and Migration program (2006-2011), funded under the Women&amp;rsquo;s Rights and Citizenship initiative, and the subsequent Migration, Gender and Social Justice (MGSJ) synthesis project (2011-2013). It aims to highlight Southern perspectives on migration, challenge dominant policy frames, and advocate for social justice by addressing power structures (gender, class, race/ethnicity, generation) that create inequalities in migration institutions. The focus is on human insecurity—vulnerabilities in livelihoods, rights, and dignity—while emphasizing women&amp;rsquo;s experiences, though it also explores masculinities and legal liminality. The book includes policy briefs for advocacy and is available free at SpringerLink.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
