<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing Sample on Zhenting HE</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/writing-sample/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing Sample on Zhenting HE</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/writing-sample/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing Practice|A Study of Women in Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s Films</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/05/15/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/05/15/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recall the penultimate page of my recently concluded dissertation, wherein I wrote, &amp;ldquo;It was a novel experience to engage in academic writing, and I found it most agreeable.&amp;rdquo; I would like to express my gratitude to my parents for their unwavering support and affection. I would like to express my gratitude to my teachers and friends for their companionship. I would like to express my gratitude to the instructors for providing me with a wealth of inspiration and ideas. I now turn to the subject of writing. I would like to express my gratitude to all those engaged in academic pursuits. To us, collectively. I would like to express my gratitude to the universe. The act of enforcing rules and cooperating with those that one does not agree with is a stifling and politically depressing process. My academic training illuminated a previously obscure area, akin to the sudden illumination of a dark room. I was fortunate to have a responsive and guiding mentor. It is unclear whether this was a means of evading reality or a genuine interest in academia. However, it is evident that my initial academic training has already had an impact on my career plans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
