<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-Writing Sample on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/-writing-sample/</link>
    <description>Recent content in -Writing Sample on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/-writing-sample/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing Practice|Relational Practices of Digital Mourning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/12/28/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/12/28/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Original title: Relational Practices of Digital Mourning Through the Lens of Continuing Bonds&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study explores the changes in the object, time, and space of digital mourning relative to traditional mourning, as well as the role of technology and its impact on socio-emotional connections. Through semi-structured in-depth interviews with 35 individuals who honored non-family members and friends on social media, the study found that the object of digital mourning extends to non-family members, that mourning is not strictly limited in time, and can be instantaneous or continuous; and that spatially it occurs in virtual space, breaking down physical spatial constraints. The spread of technology, the expansion of social networks, and the convenience of social media are the main drivers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing Practice|Aesthetics as an Invisible Power: A Chronological Examination Based on Youth&#39;s Cultural Consumption of Celebrities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/07/12/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/07/12/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As one of the most prevalent symbols in media culture, celebrity has an equally important influence on the aesthetic culture of society at large. Based on this, this study conducted in-depth interviews with 27 individuals from different generations, aiming to reveal the changes in the consumption of celebrity symbols by Chinese youth, and to explore the role of aesthetic power in this field. It is found that the changes in individuals’ aesthetic experiences not only reflect the ideologies and social disciplines of different eras, but also the process of consumers adjusting their aesthetics for greater exchange value. This paper asserts that the process of celebrity consumption is an intertwining of aesthetic change and fantasy overflow in reality, reflecting the complex aesthetic mechanisms and cultural dynamics in consumer society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
