<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visual Research on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/visual-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visual Research on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/visual-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visual Research|&#39;Southbound and Northbound&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/09/30/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/09/30/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This documentary represents the culmination of the Documentary Theory and Practice final assignment, which my group and I completed in June 2021. The group included Xiaoqing Lin, Xinyan Hu, and Yuting Zhou.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fs0eKWFKY6I?si=zshHu17F1S8e9HHF&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Southbound and Northbound&lt;/a &gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This documentary is all about showcasing the genuine, authentic ecosystem of Beixiazhu, which is known as the “No. 1 Village of Live Streaming Influencers.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The title “Southbound and Northbound” has a double meaning. On the one hand, it shows how lots of streamers are coming from all over the country, hoping to make it big in the live streaming economy. On the other hand, it suggests that this place has trouble keeping people around for long. Many people try it for a while and then move on, becoming just passing through. This kind of transience isn’t just a feature of Beixiazhu; it’s also a reflection of the fast-changing dynamics behind the live streaming economy. Beixiazhu is located in Yiwu, Zhejiang Province, and it&amp;rsquo;s known as the “No. 1 Village of Live Streaming Influencers.” Streamers, suppliers, and entrepreneurs from all over the country come together here to form a complex yet highly efficient commercial ecosystem, using the internet to promote products across the country and even globally. But there are some big challenges lurking beneath the surface. These include intense competition in the industry, the unpredictability of traffic platforms, and the high turnover of participants. This place is both a stage for dreams and a destination where dreams are shattered, which makes it an especially compelling subject for us to explore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visual Research|Reclaiming Paradise: Spotlight on Underage Sexual Assault</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/05/20/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 15:20:57 -1800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/05/20/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creation is inspired by reality. We chose the topic of sexual abuse of minors because it is a heartbreaking, highly sensitive, and complex social issue that, unfortunately, has not gained widespread attention. Notable cases, such as the 2019 molestation of a young girl by NPC deputy Wang Zhenhua, the 2020 sexual abuse of an adopted daughter by Bao Yuming, and South Korea&amp;rsquo;s Nth Room scandal, have made this issue more profoundly real for our team. These incidents have underscored the severe impact of child sexual abuse, revealing how the safe and sunny world that should belong to children is, in some ways, vanishing—transformed into something more like Fang Siqi’s tragic world.&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Reclaiming%20Paradise_08.png&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;News of sexual abuse of children&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visual Research|Non-Genetic Heritage &#39;The Entertainer or Craftsman&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/03/21/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 15:20:57 -1800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/03/21/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This documentary represents the culmination of the Basic Television Program final assignment, which my group and I completed between October 2020 and January 2021. The group included Xiaoqing Lin, Xinyan Hu, and Yuting Zhou.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mXsrzq0FnhA?si=GMu_EhblVJ7GlBLt&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Entertainer or Craftsman&lt;/a &gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chinese culture is replete with a plethora of intangible cultural heritage, teeming with resplendent historical recollections and profound cultural tenets. It constitutes an invaluable component of our collective heritage. Nevertheless, in the contemporary era, a plethora of promising avenues are emerging to safeguard these priceless intangible competencies from being eroded. In a novel approach, some intangible heritage inheritors are charting a unique course by integrating traditional skills with contemporary media communication in innovative and engaging ways. This remarkable documentary provides a comprehensive examination of the exceptional experience of an NGT inheritor. He does not merely adhere to the techniques inherited from his parents; he also assumes the initiative of joining an MCN (Multi-Channel Network) organization. By organizing and leading a professional team, he has established a highly regarded account, &amp;ldquo;Intangible Bamboo Weaving,&amp;rdquo; on the Jittery Voice platform. The account has amassed an impressive 3.874 million subscribers and a total of 38.931 million likes. The account is achieving remarkable results. It is facilitating a novel understanding of non-heritage cultures. Moreover, it is revitalizing traditional skills in a novel manner. The account is attracting a significant number of younger users.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
