<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SPSS on Zhenting HE</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/spss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SPSS on Zhenting HE</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/spss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 19.0|Logistic Regression</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/07/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/07/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;logistic-regression&#34;&gt;Logistic Regression&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Logistic regression is used to predict a binary outcome variable (e.g., Will this customer churn? Will a consumer purchase a product?). It is developed from linear regression and is specifically used when the dependent variable is binary. Logistic regression is widely applied in:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Impact Factor Analysis&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Outcome Prediction (similar to regression analysis)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The core idea of logistic regression is to estimate the probability of a certain outcome (1 or 0) given predictor variables.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 18.0|Simple Linear Regression</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/06/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/06/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;linear-regression&#34;&gt;Linear Regression&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Linear regression is a statistical method used to study the relationship between two or more variables. In simple linear regression, we explore the linear relationship between an independent variable (X) and a dependent variable (Y). The model estimates the regression coefficients using the least squares method, which are then used to predict the value of the dependent variable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;simple-linear-regression-analysis&#34;&gt;Simple Linear Regression Analysis&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The core of simple linear regression analysis is modeling through the linear equation ( Y = \beta_0 + \beta_1 X + \epsilon ), where:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 17.0|Cluster Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/05/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/05/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-to-cluster-analysis&#34;&gt;Introduction to Cluster Analysis&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cluster analysis is a statistical method used to classify objects or data points into groups (clusters) based on their similarities. The goal of cluster analysis is to partition the data into clusters where members within a cluster are more similar to each other than to those in other clusters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cluster analysis is widely used in various fields such as market research, biology, and social sciences to identify natural groupings in data, helping to reveal patterns and insights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 16.0|Reliability and Validity Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/04/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/04/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;reliability-analysis&#34;&gt;Reliability Analysis&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reliability refers to the stability and consistency of a measurement tool, assessing whether the tool can produce consistent results across different times or situations. Common methods to assess reliability include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Test-Retest Method: Administer the same questionnaire to the same group at different time points and calculate the correlation between the two sets of results, assessing the stability of the measurement tool.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Equivalent-Forms Method: Use two measurement tools that are similar in content and difficulty, administer them to the same group, and calculate the correlation between the two results.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Split-Half Method: Divide a questionnaire into two halves and calculate the correlation between the two halves to assess internal consistency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cronbach’s α Coefficient: This coefficient is used to assess the internal consistency of a scale, typically applied to multiple-choice questionnaires. The higher the Cronbach’s α value, the higher the reliability of the scale. Generally, a value above 0.7 indicates good reliability.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cronbach’s α Reliability Table:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 15.0|Correlation Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/03/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/03/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;concept-and-methods-of-correlation-analysis&#34;&gt;Concept and Methods of Correlation Analysis&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Correlation analysis is a statistical method used to assess the degree of relationship between two or more variables. It helps to explore whether a dependency exists between the variables and measures the strength and direction of this relationship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In correlation analysis, the relationship between variables is categorized into two types:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Functional Relationship: The value of one variable can be uniquely determined by another variable based on a known functional relationship (e.g., area and radius of a circle, sales quantity and revenue).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Statistical Relationship: The variables exhibit a relationship, but one variable cannot uniquely determine the value of the other (e.g., income and consumption, height and genetics).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Types of Correlation Relationships:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 14.0|Analysis of Variance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/02/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/02/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;one-way-anova-single-factor-analysis-of-variance&#34;&gt;One-Way ANOVA (Single-Factor Analysis of Variance)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Definitions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Independent Variable (Categorical Variable): This is the factor or grouping variable. In One-Way ANOVA, this variable should be categorical, representing different groups (e.g., different treatment types, different gender categories).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dependent Variable (Continuous Variable): This is the variable that is measured or observed. The values of this variable are expected to differ depending on the levels of the independent variable (e.g., test scores, weight, income).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Types of Variables:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 13.0|Mean Comparison - Independent Samples t-test</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/01/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/01/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In statistical analysis, the Independent Samples t-test is used to compare the means of two independent samples to determine if there is a significant difference between them. When you have a binary categorical variable (e.g., gender, smoking status) and a continuous variable (e.g., income, age), you can use the Independent Samples t-test to check whether the means of these two independent samples are equal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;mean-comparison---independent-samples-t-test---comparing-means-of-binary-variables&#34;&gt;Mean Comparison - Independent Samples t-test - Comparing Means of Binary Variables&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Independent Samples t-test is used in the following situations:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 12.0|Chi-Square Test and Association Strength Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/31/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/31/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-bivariate-statistical-analysis--chi-square-test-in-cross-tabulations&#34;&gt;1. Bivariate Statistical Analysis — Chi-Square Test in Cross Tabulations**&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Definition&#xA;The Chi-Square test is a statistical method used to examine whether there is an association between two categorical variables. It compares observed frequencies to expected frequencies and determines whether the variables are independent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Steps of the Chi-Square Test&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Construct a Contingency Table: Organize the data of the two categorical variables in a table format.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Calculate Expected Frequencies: Under the assumption of no association, calculate the expected frequency for each cell based on the row and column marginal totals.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Calculate the Chi-Square Statistic: Use the formula&lt;br&gt;&#xA;[&#xA;\chi^2 = \sum \frac{(O - E)^2}{E}&#xA;]&#xA;where ( O ) is the observed frequency, and ( E ) is the expected frequency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Compare the Chi-Square Value to the Critical Value: Using the degrees of freedom and significance level (usually 0.05), refer to the Chi-Square distribution table to decide whether to reject the null hypothesis (no association).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hypothesis Testing&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 11.0|Descriptive Statistics: Mean Calculation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/30/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/30/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In descriptive statistics, the mean (also called the average) is one of the most fundamental measures used to represent the central tendency of a dataset. It is often used to summarize a set of values with a single number that best represents the entire distribution of data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;definition&#34;&gt;Definition&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mean is calculated by summing all the values in a dataset and then dividing by the number of values. It is commonly used to understand the overall level of a dataset, such as the average score of students in a class, the average income in a region, or the average temperature of a month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 10.0|Bivariate Statistical Analysis - Crosstabulation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/29/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/29/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In statistical analysis, it is often necessary to examine the data distribution of multiple variables under different values to gain a deeper understanding of the interactions and relationships between these variables. This analysis is referred to as crosstabulation analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Crosstabulation analysis not only lists the frequency distribution of cross-grouped variables but also assesses whether there is independence or a certain degree of correlation between the two variables. To determine the correlation between variables, relying solely on frequency distribution data is insufficient; statistical measures of correlation between variables and non-parametric testing methods must be used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 9.0|Descriptive Statistical Analysis - Basic Questionnaire Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/28/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/28/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(1) Basic Statistical Analysis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Principles of Descriptive Statistics&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To analyze the overall characteristics of the research subject, it is not necessary to study each unit within the population. In communication and sociology, more often, sampling methods are used, and according to the principle of randomness, only a portion of units (usually called a sample) is selected from the entire population for calculation and study. For each sample group, statistical measures should first be calculated to make an estimation and inference about the population characteristics with a certain degree of reliability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 8.0|Data Cleaning and Transformation Operations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/27/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/27/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-transformation-functions-in-spss&#34;&gt;Data Transformation Functions in SPSS&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-count&#34;&gt;1. Count&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Count function is used when you want to count the number of occurrences of a particular value or category within a set of variables.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps-to-use-count&#34;&gt;Steps to Use Count:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Select &amp;ldquo;Transform &amp;gt; Count&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the SPSS menu, go to &lt;code&gt;Transform &amp;gt; Count...&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Choose Variables:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the dialog box, select the variables that you want to count the occurrences of a specific value.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Define the Criteria:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 7.0|Data Sorting, Filtering, and Handling Missing Values</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/26/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/26/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;spss-main-interface-and-data-import&#34;&gt;SPSS Main Interface and Data Import&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-spsss-main-interface&#34;&gt;1. SPSS&amp;rsquo;s Main Interface&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-spss-has-two-primary-windows&#34;&gt;(1) SPSS has two primary windows:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data Editor (Data View):Where you input and view the dataset. You can work with variables and cases in this window.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Output Viewer:Displays the results of your analyses, including tables, charts, and statistical tests. It stores output in a &lt;code&gt;.spv&lt;/code&gt; file format.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-two-main-windows-and-file-formats&#34;&gt;(2) Two main windows and file formats:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data Editor (Data View):&lt;code&gt;.sav&lt;/code&gt; file (SPSS dataset format)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Output Viewer:&lt;code&gt;.spv&lt;/code&gt; file (SPSS output format)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-third-window-syntax-editor&#34;&gt;(3) Third Window: Syntax Editor&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is used for writing and executing SPSS commands or syntax scripts, saved as &lt;code&gt;.sps&lt;/code&gt; files.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-spss-can-import-or-open-common-data-formats&#34;&gt;(4) SPSS can import or open common data formats:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SPSS .sav files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Excel .xls or .xlsx files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CSV (Comma-separated values) files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Other typeslike tab-delimited files or even text files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-each-window-allows-you-to-run-data-processing-and-analysis-through-menus&#34;&gt;(5) Each window allows you to run data processing and analysis through menus.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-importing-external-data&#34;&gt;2. Importing External Data&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you import external data (like Excel, CSV, etc.) into SPSS, consider the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 6.0|Merging and Splitting of Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/23/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/23/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data merging and splitting are commonly used techniques for organizing and analyzing data more effectively. For example, merging data from different sources or splitting data based on certain variables to make comparisons or analyses more specific.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-splitting-split-file&#34;&gt;Data Splitting (Split File)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data splitting means dividing the dataset into subsets based on certain criteria, such as gender, GPA, or any other variable. This is useful for analyzing the data within different groups.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 5.0|Importing External Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/22/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/22/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-spsss-main-interface&#34;&gt;1. SPSS&amp;rsquo;s Main Interface&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-spss-has-two-primary-windows&#34;&gt;(1) SPSS has two primary windows:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data Editor (Data View): Where you input and view the dataset. You can work with variables and cases in this window.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Output Viewer: Displays the results of your analyses, including tables, charts, and statistical tests. It stores output in a &lt;code&gt;.spv&lt;/code&gt; file format.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-two-main-windows-and-file-formats&#34;&gt;(2) Two main windows and file formats:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data Editor (Data View): &lt;code&gt;.sav&lt;/code&gt; file (SPSS dataset format)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Output Viewer: &lt;code&gt;.spv&lt;/code&gt; file (SPSS output format)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-third-window-syntax-editor&#34;&gt;(3) Third Window: Syntax Editor&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is used for writing and executing SPSS commands or syntax scripts, saved as &lt;code&gt;.sps&lt;/code&gt; files.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-spss-can-import-or-open-common-data-formats&#34;&gt;(4) SPSS can import or open common data formats:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SPSS .sav files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Excel .xls or .xlsx files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CSV (Comma-separated values) files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Other types like tab-delimited files or even text files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-each-window-allows-you-to-run-data-processing-and-analysis-through-menus&#34;&gt;(5) Each window allows you to run data processing and analysis through menus.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-importing-external-data&#34;&gt;2. Importing External Data&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you import external data (like Excel, CSV, etc.) into SPSS, consider the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 4.0|Comparison of Data Measurement Scales</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/20/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/20/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-review&#34;&gt;Data Review&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Concept:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The researcher conducts an initial review of the collected raw data, correcting errors and removing incomplete, incorrect, or unusable responses (such as blank or irrelevant answers). The goal is to ensure the data’s accuracy, completeness, and authenticity, which lays the foundation for subsequent data entry and analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Completeness Review: Ensuring all necessary data fields are filled in, without missing responses.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Accuracy Review: Checking for errors or inconsistencies in the data, such as incorrect or out-of-range values.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-conversion&#34;&gt;Data Conversion&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data conversion involves translating the responses to questionnaire items into numerical values that can be recognized and processed by a computer for statistical analysis.&#xA;Example of questionnaire items and their numeric conversion:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 3.0|Comparison of Data Measurement Scales</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/19/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/19/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;measurement-scale-and-statistical-analysis&#34;&gt;Measurement Scale and Statistical Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Measurement Scale&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Data Processing Methods&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Statistical Analysis Methods&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Nominal Scale&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;No order, only classification&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Frequency analysis, Chi-square test&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Chi-square test, Contingency table analysis&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Ordinal Scale&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Ordered, but not equidistant&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Median, Rank-sum test&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Mann-Whitney U test, Rank-sum test&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Interval Scale&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Ordered, equidistant, but no absolute zero&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Mean, Standard deviation, Difference analysis&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;t-test, ANOVA, Correlation analysis&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Ratio Scale&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Ordered, equidistant, and with absolute zero&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;All mathematical operations, Mean, Standard deviation, Proportions, etc.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;t-test, ANOVA, Correlation analysis, Regression analysis&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Choosing the appropriate measurement scale is crucial for more accurate statistical analysis in SPSS. By understanding the nature of your data, you can select the most suitable statistical methods for analysis. This ensures the results are reliable and aligned with the scale of measurement, helping to prevent inappropriate assumptions or calculations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 2.0|What is SPSS?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/18/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/18/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-spss&#34;&gt;What is SPSS?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;definition-and-overview&#34;&gt;Definition and Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SPSS (Statistical Package for the Social Sciences) is one of the world’s leading statistical analysis software programs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Over nearly 40 years of development, it has gained a large global user base.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SPSS provides an intuitive Windows-based interface, allowing users to easily manage and analyze data for scientific research.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-spss&#34;&gt;History of SPSS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In 1968, three Stanford University students developed the first SPSS system.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In 1975, based on this system, they founded SPSS Inc. in Chicago.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Initially, SPSS stood for &amp;ldquo;Statistical Package for the Social Sciences&amp;rdquo;, emphasizing its role in social science research.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In 2000, the full name was officially changed to &amp;ldquo;Statistical Product and Service Solutions&amp;rdquo;, highlighting its broader statistical applications.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-functions-of-spss&#34;&gt;Core Functions of SPSS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data Management – Import, clean, and organize datasets.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Statistical Analysis – Perform descriptive and inferential statistics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Graphical Analysis – Generate visual representations like histograms, scatter plots, and trend lines.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Output Management – Customize and export analysis results.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;main-spss-interface&#34;&gt;Main SPSS Interface&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;spss-key-windows&#34;&gt;SPSS Key Windows&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data Editor Window – Displays datasets in two views:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS 1.0|Establishing the Concept of &#39;Quantitative&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/17/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/17/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;definition-of-quantitative&#34;&gt;Definition of &amp;ldquo;Quantitative&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Quantitative&amp;rdquo; refers to an attribute that exists in numerical form and can be measured.&#xA;The purpose of quantitative research is to discover general behavioral patterns and provide universal explanations for phenomena in various environments. It is typically conducted to derive statistical results for a specific research population.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Common Types of Quantitative Data:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Height&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Weight&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Age&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Income&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;research-process-flowchart&#34;&gt;Research Process Flowchart&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;define-research-objectives&#34;&gt;Define Research Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Clearly state the aim of the research.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identify key questions and expected outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;conceptualization&#34;&gt;Conceptualization&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Develop a theoretical framework.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Define key concepts and relationships.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;select-research-methods&#34;&gt;Select Research Methods&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Choose qualitative, quantitative, or mixed methods.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Determine data collection techniques.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;observation&#34;&gt;Observation&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gather data through fieldwork, surveys, or experiments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ensure reliability and validity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;population--sampling&#34;&gt;Population &amp;amp; Sampling&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Define the target population.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Select sampling methods and size.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;operationalization&#34;&gt;Operationalization&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Convert concepts into measurable variables.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Develop instruments like questionnaires or coding schemes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-processing&#34;&gt;Data Processing&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Clean, organize, and prepare data for analysis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Handle missing or inconsistent data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;analysis&#34;&gt;Analysis&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Apply statistical or qualitative analysis techniques.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interpret findings and draw conclusions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;application--review&#34;&gt;Application &amp;amp; Review&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Apply results to real-world scenarios or theoretical discussions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reflect on the research process and suggest improvements.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;quantitative-statistical-analysis&#34;&gt;Quantitative Statistical Analysis&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Statistical analysis refers to the application of statistical methods to analyze collected data quantitatively. This approach reveals the internal numerical relationships, patterns, and developments within the data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPSS Learning Notes|Easy to Follow &amp; Review Later!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/16/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/16/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve been organizing my SPSS learning materials, and I thought, why not share them here? This will be a great way for anyone interested in quantitative research to get started, and for me to review whenever needed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this series, I’ll be importing key parts from the SPSS courses I’ve taken, breaking them down into simple, practical steps. Whether you’re new to SPSS or just need a quick refresher, you’ll find these posts useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
