<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic Journey on Zhenting HE</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/academic-journey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Academic Journey on Zhenting HE</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/academic-journey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflections and Questions on the Speech of  November 25</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/11/26/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/11/26/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the academic lecture, four research methods were introduced: classic ethnography, dialogical and biographical approaches, cultural semiotics, and neo-/post-Marxist approaches.&#xA;I have two related questions:&#xA;First, these four methods may differ in their theoretical foundations and epistemologies. Is it truly feasible to integrate them in a single study? If so, what theoretical or methodological considerations should be taken into account to ensure a coherent integration?&#xA;Second, at the operational level, how can researchers minimize the disparity between their own social position and that of the research participants? As researchers, we inevitably form certain value judgments from reading extensive literature and background materials before entering the field. How, then, can one avoid adopting an “arrogant” stance toward participants? What strategies or practices can help maintain sensitivity and respect, ensuring that the research process is conducted in an ethical and equitable manner?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to have an emotional connection to one’s research? </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/09/22/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/09/22/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One question I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering today is that, for me, this emotional connection feels more like a “bond” rather than a single-layered “passion.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure exactly when I first encountered feminist studies. If I had to pinpoint a moment, it might be the 2018 #MeToo movement, which had a profound impact on me (though I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize it at the time). Then, in 2020, the Bao Yuming incident unfolded. I pored over every accessible report, dozens of academic papers, and hundreds of news articles. Starting from scratch, I learned software design to create an information visualization for child protection, alongside designing related merchandise and a WeChat public account. To this day, I can still recall the visceral nausea I felt upon seeing the word “sexual assault.” Yet I hoped my practical efforts could help more people gain fundamental awareness through this work. I aimed to educate—and indeed, I succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Academic Reflections|Why write this thesis?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/06/21/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/06/21/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This research initially set out to examine the phenomenon of empathy in the social media era. In contemporary society, individuals appear more willing to express empathy and find it easier to elicit empathetic responses from others. This observation prompted me to question whether social media has genuinely fostered moral improvement. To address this, we reviewed several theoretical perspectives and encountered the concept of the “empathy machine,” a term for technological systems designed to evoke and stimulate empathy. However, through discussions with my advisor, we began to question the depth of this empathy. Based on my observations and experiences, such empathy does not appear to drive substantive societal change. For example, it remains unclear whether the lives of people with disabilities, women, or sexual minorities have significantly improved as a result of social media. Analyzing data from presentation slides and case studies referenced in the article&amp;rsquo;s introduction suggests a less optimistic outcome. This led me to consider whether empathy on social media primarily functions as emotional consumption, addressing only the surface of social change rather than facilitating the transformative emotional rituals of the past. Recognizing the significance of this question, we determined that the “empathy machine” framework required additional critical theoretical resources. Among the theories considered, Marxist political economy emerged as the most relevant and incisive for our research, ultimately shaping our current analytical framework.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mindset during Application|Keep Calm, Stay Positive!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/05/01/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/05/01/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Applications can truly be a challenge, a test of academic potential, language skills, and mental resilience. At first, my mindset was: “I’ll leave the choice to the professors and let them decide if I’m suited for academia.” But now, I feel differently: “No matter what, I’ll find a way to make this path work.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maybe it takes going through this process to truly understand myself and figure out what I really want. The road ahead in research will probably be even more complicated and challenging, but in a way, the PhD application stage already sets the tone. If I make it, I’ll take on the next phase of training. If I don’t, then I’ve still chosen a way to engage with the world. Either way, it’s not a loss. It’s just a different way of living. In the end, depth and joy are mostly about perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Academic Reflections|Game with Me? Cheating between Rules and Freedom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/11/30/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/11/30/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The game itself exists independently of the individual, following a spontaneous order in terms of chances and rules. When a decision is made to participate in a game, the act itself is driven by a clear purpose, such as participation, experience or victory. This order produces an alignment of advantages, underpinned by the design of the game&amp;rsquo;s rules and the operation of its procedures. The player, in this process, appears to metamorphose into a digital entity, endowed with roles to facilitate the game&amp;rsquo;s objectives.In essence, the programmed player and the &amp;lsquo;self-programmed&amp;rsquo; game are reciprocally fulfilling, establishing a cyclical and dynamic relationship (pivotal questions to ponder include: &amp;lsquo;Am I the player of the game, or is the game the player of me?&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Is the game the player of me?&amp;rsquo;). The game is a dynamic of mutual fulfilment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Academic Reflections|The Sustainability of Digital Nomads&#39; Mobility?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/10/27/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/10/27/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The term “digital nomad” was first coined by researchers Makimoto and Manners in their 1997 publication Digital Nomad. In their work, the authors put forward an illuminating theoretical perspective: humanity&amp;rsquo;s inclination towards migration may stem from our ancestors&amp;rsquo; nomadic way of life – a view widely endorsed within the field of sociology. Psychologists attribute it to innate human curiosity, while cynics view it as a direct manifestation of escapism. Regardless of interpretation, it appears to be an inherent aspect of human nature (Jardis.com, 2021). The convergence of technology, globalisation, and evolving work paradigms has catalysed the phenomenon of “digital nomadism”, challenging established norms surrounding the nature of work. Digital nomadism signifies not merely the emergence of a new form of employment, but also the advent of a novel lifestyle situated between “travelling” and “migrating”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
