<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>It&#39;s Just an Experience on Zhenting HE</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/its-just-an-experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in It&#39;s Just an Experience on Zhenting HE</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/its-just-an-experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The End of A Chapter in Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/05/30/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/05/30/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All theory is gray, but the golden tree of life springs ever green.&amp;rdquo; I originally intended to borrow this line from Faust, feigning a sense of depth to mark the end of these four years. Yet at this moment, what floods my mind is not a series of adjectives but vivid memories of events and specific people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My parents, who have stood unwaveringly behind me since the day I was born, have been my greatest support. My advisor PENG, whose thoughtful guidance helped me realize my passion for theory far outweighs my interest in industry work, gave my life plan a new direction. And all the friends I have met along the way. Together, we ran through campuses and cities, dedicating ourselves to public service. We insisted on pursuing in-depth reporting and even founded our own magazine. We spent countless hours practicing in the taekwondo gym and the dance studio, and we honed our communication skills through student leadership roles. These experiences enriched my college years beyond measure and helped me discover a part of myself, someone who cherishes solitude more than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
