<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oral Presentation on Zhenting HE</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/oral-presentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oral Presentation on Zhenting HE</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/oral-presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oral Presentation|Reporting on Digital Feminist Working Practices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/06/25/road-not-taken/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/06/25/road-not-taken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This research was presented orally at the ICA. It is closely connected not only to my own experiences as a woman but also to my long-term engagement in this digital fieldwork. The project focuses on the working practices of digital feminists in China. This study is significant for several reasons: on the one hand, it helps reveal how feminists organize, disseminate ideas, and engage in social practice within digital spaces, thereby enriching our understanding of contemporary gender practices in China; on the other hand, it explores the interactions between digital technologies and social movements, providing new perspectives for understanding social action, public discourse, and gender politics in the digital era. By combining personal experience with fieldwork observation, I am able to gain a deeper understanding of the strategies, methods, and social impacts of digital feminist practices, while laying a foundation for further research in this area. Compared to my previous presentation, I approached this session with greater composure, feeling more confident and at ease in sharing my insights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oral Presentation|First Participation in Academic Conference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/07/02/road-not-taken/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/07/02/road-not-taken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of March, I was thrilled to discover the incredible opportunity to submit my first academic training paper to IAMCR! I was thrilled to give it a try! I was thrilled to receive an acceptance notification just a few weeks later! I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to say that my first academic paper was accepted by an international conference, which marks the start of my journey into formal academic presentations!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was so excited to attend the conference that I booked a flight on June 29th! I departed from Beijing and flew to Auckland, New Zealand, where I transferred to Christchurch. This journey was a thrilling adventure, marking my first international academic trip and the start of an amazing journey! Late June to early July is winter in New Zealand, and the crisp air and vivid blue skies were refreshing. Christchurch, with its classical and elegant architecture, tidy streets, and serene atmosphere, exuded a natural purity that felt completely different from the Northern Hemisphere. I was secretly hoping that if all went well, I might return here in the future, participating in academic activities with more composure and confidence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
