<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pray for a Return to Normalcy on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/pray-for-a-return-to-normalcy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pray for a Return to Normalcy on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/pray-for-a-return-to-normalcy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Savoring Beijing: My Top Food Highlights!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/01/09/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/01/09/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I saw the news, it suddenly reminded me of a year when I traveled to Beijing three times in three months to handle various documents. Of course, every trip to Beijing meant an opportunity to dive into its food scene. Here are my top three favorite dishes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shabu-shabu – absolutely unbeatable, my top pick!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pear soup – sweet but perfectly balanced, earning second place.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir-fried vegetables – from a restaurant famous for its roast duck, a solid third.&#xA;While Beijing’s food is incredible, I can’t help but miss Cantonese cuisine. I’m longing for those familiar flavors and hoping this chapter ends soon. We all deserve carefree and joyful days again!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Beijing%20food-01.jpg&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Beijing Food Map 1, including shabu-shabu, roast duck, lo mein, small hanging pear soup, fried noodles, bean curd dumplings, rice noodles, fried eggs, cold skin&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Beijing%20food-02.jpg&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Beijing Food Map 2, including fried hechibanko, dan dan noodles, wontons, grilled cold noodles, boiled language, Japanese restaurants in hutongs and Osaka cuisine in Liangmaqiao&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
