<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-Film on Zhenting HE</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/-film/</link>
    <description>Recent content in -Film on Zhenting HE</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/-film/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How is &#39;Science Fiction&#39; and &#39;Real Perception&#39; Possible in Science Fiction Documentaries?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/10/18/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/10/18/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The question of how &amp;lsquo;science fiction&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;real perception&amp;rsquo; are possible in science fiction documentaries is a complex one.After watching  &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1433058/&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Life after People&lt;/a &gt;, it suddenly occurs to me that &amp;lsquo;science fiction&amp;rsquo; has distinctive attributes of the future and the unknown, whereas &amp;lsquo;documentary&amp;rsquo; is attached to history and the known.With its unique narrative mode, the science fiction documentary film cleverly blends the past and the future, fiction and documentary in a common narrative space by means of visualising the future. Another salient issue that science fiction documentaries cannot avoid is that of authenticity. This issue stems from the very concept of documentary film itself, and since Grierson&amp;rsquo;s seminal definition of the genre, there have been controversies concerning the authenticity of documentary film. The concept of authenticity pertains to the foundational issue of human existence, delineates the status of human relations with human beings, nature and society, and serves as the fundamental premise for the construction of a worldview, in addition to serving as the basis for all theoretical knowledge and practical experience.As a philosophical metaphysical assumption, reality is conceived as a product of human imagination, created ex nihilo by human reason in order to achieve an understanding of the world. The existing research on science fiction documentary has not yet produced a clear and normative definition of the concept. However, the existing definitions of science fiction works and documentaries can help to further illuminate the concept. In essence, both documentaries and science fiction films are conceptualised as depictions of human cognition informed by tangible experiences. However, a fundamental distinction emerges when analysing the underlying motivations behind these genres. Documentaries prioritise the documentation of reality, whereas science fiction documentaries are predicated on factual information employed for the purposes of expression or creation. In science fiction films, the depiction of reality often serves to advance the narrative arc, superseding its role in documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
