<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Zhenting HE</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Zhenting HE</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Photographic Record | Where the Forest Keeps Its Secrets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/11/10/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/11/10/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took a few pictures during the winter, capturing moments of quiet life. It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely way to document my growth and the traces of my existence. Some of my photos are taken during everyday life, while others are captured during hikes or travels.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Heidelberg/lecture.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Figure 1: Attended the lecture in full and asked questions to the professor afterward.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Heidelberg/Exterior.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Figure 2: I hiked up to the castle and found the path shrouded in fog.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images//Heidelberg/Morning.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Figure 3: One morning, I was downstairs chatting with a friend and her dad when I noticed the construction site across the street.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images//Heidelberg/oarsman.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Figure 4: Watching people paddle in the winter, I suddenly remembered how long I’ve wanted to go boating. I’ll definitely make it happen next time.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images//Heidelberg/forest.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Figure 5: Mid-autumn, I went hiking and walked through a forest of muted reds and golds. The leaves whispered underfoot, the air was crisp, and the forest remained quietly still—Die Wälder schweigen.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images//Heidelberg/Snapshot.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Figure 6: After finishing my day’s tasks, I walked home and was suddenly struck by the beauty of the sky’s colors.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images//Heidelberg/Shepherd.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Figure 7: Cheerful German Shepherd&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photographic Record | Guangzhou Daily Life 2.0</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/09/01/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/09/01/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-09-01,01.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;September 1, 2025, Girls in front of the convenience store on the first day of school&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-09-01,02.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;September 1, 2025, Two boys walking home for lunch, one ahead of the other&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-09-01,03.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;September 1, 2025, People gathered around the fruit stall&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-09-01,04.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;September 1, 2025, Elderly folks checking travel plans outside the tour agency&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-09-01,05.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;September 1, 2025, The green light at noon in the office building&amp;#39;s connecting corridor&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-09-01,06.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;August 31, 2025, The evening glow at Luhu Park&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photographic Record | Guangzhou Daily Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/08/15/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/08/15/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-07-29.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;July 29, 2025, A worker pushing a garbage bin in the neighborhood&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-07-31,01.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;July 31, 2025, An elderly person riding an electric bike passing by&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-07-31,02.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;July 31, 2025, Two elderly people walking in different directions near a construction site&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-07-31,03.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;July 31, 2025, A woman standing in front of a shop, behind an electric scooter&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-07-31,04.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;July 31, 2025, Elderly people chatting in the community&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-08-02.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;August 2, 2025, An elderly person waiting for the rain to stop in the community&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-08-12.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;August 12, 2025, A woman working in a garment factory&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Guangzhou/2025-08-15.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;August 15, 2025, An elderly person carrying scrap near Taojin Subway Station&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volunteer Experience|Caring for Women and Children in Urban Villages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/04/23/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/04/23/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What makes Shenzhen truly special to me is the warmth and resilience of its people. This spirit inspired me to become part of the Green Rose Volunteer Community, where we work to uplift women and children in urban villages. Every Friday night, I host film screenings for local kids, sharing stories that spark curiosity and encourage growth. Watching the community evolve week by week, I see Shenzhen’s legacy come alive through the small, sustainable changes we create together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Exhibition|The World&#39;s First Cologne &amp; Perfume Museum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/11/23/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/11/23/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I think of the city of Cologne, the first thing that comes to mind is Cologne Cathedral. But when I came to Cologne and learned about its history, I realised that the church hadn&amp;rsquo;t even been built when Farina was founded 300 years ago. Cologne Cathedral was not officially completed until 1880, but the city had become famous for its cologne, Oudtclum, long before that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1708, at the age of 23, Farina left her home in northern Italy and travelled north along the Rhine to Cologne. At the time, the city was attracting many people with its prosperity and reputation as the &amp;lsquo;Rome of the North&amp;rsquo;. Farina joined her brother, who had been living in Cologne for many years, where she invented a unique perfume.&#xA;In a letter to her brother, Farina described her work: &amp;ldquo;I have invented a perfume that takes you back to the rainy spring mornings of Italy. The blend of citrus, lemon, grapefruit and Italian flowers was fresh and delightful, and in 1709 the brothers officially founded the company, calling the perfume &amp;lsquo;Eau de Cologne&amp;rsquo;, meaning &amp;lsquo;water from Cologne&amp;rsquo;. Eau de Cologne&amp;rsquo;, meaning &amp;lsquo;water from Cologne&amp;rsquo;. This perfume became the origin of &amp;lsquo;cologne&amp;rsquo;. Yesterday I went to the address of the 300-year-old company, which is still open.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The First Snow of 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/11/21/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 15:20:57 -1800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/11/21/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/videos/2024%20first%20snow%20video.mp4&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;The First Snow Moment of the year!&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I saw the first snowfall of the year, and this morning it seemed to materialize as  “sunrise in the east and snow in the west”. I was reminded of the original poem, “The west is veiled in the rain, the east enjoys sunshine.My gallant is as deep in love as the day is fine. （东边日出西边雨，道是无情却有情”）” It’s from a poem called “Two Songs of the Bamboo Branch（《竹枝词二首》）” by Liu Yuxi, who was a poet during the Tang Dynasty. The poem says that while the sun is rising in the east, it is raining in the west. It also says that the sky is not clear but there is clear sunshine. The poem talks about the weather, but the author uses a clever pun, “sunny - love,” to write about both weather and love. The sun is shining in the east and raining in the west, so I thought he was heartless, but he still has love.&#xA;Kind of like my current situation and state of mind.&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2024%20first%20snow-01.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Window before and after the first snow&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2024%20first%20snow-02.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;The Other Side of Clear&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;Actually, the “sun snow” phenomenon is pretty straightforward. It happens when cold and warm air masses converge locally. When the cold air hits the warm air underneath, the dry cold air and warm moist air meet and form snowfall. At the same time, the clouds at the top aren&amp;rsquo;t thick enough to block the sun completely. There might be some sunlight coming through the gaps in the clouds, which will make it look like there&amp;rsquo;s sunshine and snow on the ground at the same time. Since there aren&amp;rsquo;t many clouds, “solar snow” doesn’t stick around for long. It usually happens in the 9-10 or 15-16 hour window. You don&amp;rsquo;t need fancy weather to get a short burst of snow. It&amp;rsquo;s more about enjoying the view than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Overseas Rental Experience in Germany</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/11/01/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/11/01/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before I moved to Germany, I had spent nearly 24 years living in various cities in southern China, where I was “waited on hand and foot.” The convenience of city life and a home environment where I didn’t need to worry about daily necessities made it easy to get everything I needed. However, this also meant I overlooked developing some basic self-care skills.While I&amp;rsquo;m comfortable navigating city life and can easily access convenient resources in different places, I realize that in less convenient situations, I still need practice managing various aspects of daily life independently. For instance, I know how to choose healthy restaurants to meet my nutritional needs, but if they’re closed, I find myself uncertain about preparing a quick, nutritious meal on my own. Living on my own, especially as I pursue education abroad, will undoubtedly require me to develop these skills further. I believe that this experience will help me build these essential qualities in advance, better preparing me for an independent life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Months of Missing New Zealand</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/09/02/six-months-of-missing-new-zealand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/09/02/six-months-of-missing-new-zealand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can already see that I&amp;rsquo;m going to miss the short half month I spent in New Zealand for the next six months. It all seems to have started back in February when I felt lost in life. I wanted to go into academia, but had almost no substantial work to show for it. So I decided to apply to the IAMCR and if that didn&amp;rsquo;t work out I would look for an internship. Luckily, my application was successful, which gave me a huge boost for what came next. Looking back, even if it hadn&amp;rsquo;t worked out, I would have kept going. I hope to have more time to visit New Zealand again in the future, perhaps next spring, summer or autumn! I&amp;rsquo;d love to share the details of my trip with you, but for now I&amp;rsquo;m keeping the details of hotels, restaurants and activities to myself. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, feel free to drop me a line and I&amp;rsquo;ll share them individually.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Exhibition|Revisiting Duchamp&#39;s &#39;Fountain&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/08/09/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/08/09/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Encountering Marcel Duchamp&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Fountain&amp;rsquo;at the Philadelphia Museum of Art was an unexpected but delightful surprise. Although I had long been aware of its pivotal role in the history of modern art, standing in front of the piece in person offered a profoundly different experience. This deceptively simple work, a porcelain urinal turned upside down, transcends its form to pose provocative questions: What defines art? Where are its boundaries?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Fountain.jpg&#34; width=&#34;360&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;&amp;#39;Fountain&amp;#39;, Note: The fountain in the collection of the Philadelphia Museum of Art is one of the earliest of 14 reproductions as large as the original. The signature, &amp;#39;R. Mutt 1917&amp;#39; was added by Duchamp himself in 1950.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a child, I first heard about &amp;lsquo;Fountain&amp;rsquo;through an art book, and its reputation left me puzzled. How could an ordinary urinal be considered art? It lacked the intricate craftsmanship or grandeur often associated with masterpieces in museums. More than a decade later, seeing the 1950 replica in person revived my childhood confusion, but also brought new insight. Duchamp&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Fountain&amp;rsquo;asserts that art lies not only in technical skill or aesthetic appeal, but in the artist&amp;rsquo;s power to give objects new meaning. As Timothy Rub, CEO of the Philadelphia Museum of Art, aptly observed, &amp;ldquo;A hundred years ago, &amp;lsquo;Fountain&amp;rsquo;shook the art world to its core. Artists and critics debated whether it was a masterpiece or a prank. By calling a ceramic urinal a &amp;lsquo;readymade&amp;rsquo;, Duchamp fundamentally changed the course of modern art. Today, young artists are still inspired or enraged by it. This enduring relevance underlines the importance of revisiting the piece and reflecting on its meaning a century later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Exhibition|Record of Paintings Seen at the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/08/07/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/08/07/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While sorting out my memories, I found out that the Boston Museum of Fine Arts has a description of the paintings, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to put some records of the paintings on the website and post a link to them. If you are interested in this content, you can click &lt;a href=&#39;https://collections.mfa.org/advancedsearch;jsessionid=7789F17F27257FC632ACCAEA86A506B0/&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;here&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a &gt; to go to the official website of the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston. This will also make it easier for me to recall later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing Issues|How Effective Are Financial Incentives in Motivating Employees? </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/06/17/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/06/17/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Providing financial rewards to employees for exceptional contributions is a common management practice, often seen as a way to boost motivation and performance. However, the effectiveness of such incentives varies. Sometimes, they may even produce unintended negative effects. This essay will explore how well financial and monetary rewards work as motivators and suggest other ways to encourage employee performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The impact of monetary rewards largely depends on individual needs and the workplace context. For some employees, especially those facing financial challenges, bonuses are a powerful motivator. But for others, monetary rewards can feel impersonal or inadequate. For instance, an employee who is deeply committed to their company or focused on long-term career development might feel undervalued if their efforts are recognized only with money. In such cases, financial rewards fail to satisfy deeper motivations like personal fulfillment or loyalty. Therefore, managers should carefully consider each employee’s unique contributions and preferences when deciding how to reward them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing Issues|The Influence of Global Fashion on People’s Lives </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/02/07/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/02/07/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the popularity of following fashion trends has increased significantly, shaping various aspects of daily life. This essay examines the factors contributing to the strong influence of global fashion and contends that, overall, this development produces more negative than positive effects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A primary factor behind the expanding influence of global fashion is the rapid advancement of social media. Technology companies employ algorithms to analyze user preferences and consistently promote fashion-related content on digital platforms. As a result, people are repeatedly exposed to global trends and may feel pressured to follow them. Another reason is peer influence. Fashion often becomes a common topic in social interactions, helping people connect with friends and avoid awkward conversations. Finally, economic factors also play an important role. To increase profits, fashion companies intensively market new trends, encouraging consumers to make more frequent purchases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing Issues|The Influence of Global Fashion on People’s Lives </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/02/07/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/02/07/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In contemporary society, there has been a growing shift toward online communication, replacing many traditional, in-person interactions. While online communication offers certain advantages, I firmly believe that adopting virtual communication models over traditional face-to-face communication presents more disadvantages than benefits. This essay will examine how the drawbacks of virtual communication, particularly in terms of emotional connection, physical well-being, and interpersonal relationships outweigh its convenience and accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is undeniable that the internet has enhanced certain aspects of life, particularly in terms of convenience and accessibility. Online communication allows people to stay connected with friends, family, and colleagues across geographical boundaries. If friends live in different countries, sending messages or making video calls is far quicker and more convenient than traditional methods of communication. Similarly, the internet has made professional environments more flexible, as employees can work from home or other locations without needing to be physically present in the office. This flexibility has made work more adaptable and, in some cases, more productive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Exhibition|My Zodiac Sculpture at the Metropolitan Museum of Art</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/11/25/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/11/25/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My zodiac sign is the dragon (Loong/Dragon), and when I saw these works at the Met, I immediately thought about the stark contrast between the representation of this zodiac sign in Chinese and Western contexts. The differing understandings and symbolism of the dragon between China and the West reflect the diverse interpretations of nature, social order, and morality in each culture.&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/MMA/1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Carvings of Dragon&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;In Chinese culture, the dragon is seen as a symbol of honor, good fortune, and authority, carrying profound cultural and spiritual connotations. It represents the harmony between heaven and earth, the legitimacy of imperial power, and the power of nature. The image of the Chinese dragon often conveys love, shelter, strength, and wisdom. For instance, the dragon is frequently found on imperial symbols, such as the emperor’s robe or jade seal, symbolizing a strong connection between the ruler and the deities of heaven and earth. Its esteemed status and harmonious relationship with the natural world reflect a deep respect for cosmic order and social stability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Youth Volunteer Association Yearly Memories </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/07/05/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/07/05/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I just happened to be working on the summary of the Youth Volunteer Association 2019, so I just happened to dump a copy of the English version on my website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a part of the Youth Volunteer Association for a year and a half now, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been leading activities almost every Saturday morning and afternoon. It&amp;rsquo;s been a year of growth and development for me, moving from volunteering to leading a team. When I first took over, I always felt that going to specific volunteer positions and helping specific people seemed more effective than taking on more managerial positions such as liaising and coordinating, especially for us students. I have to admit that I&amp;rsquo;m not that into spending time on these things, to be honest. I really enjoy reporting and coordinating all kinds of meetings, and reporting the progress of my work to the college and the school league committee every week. This report contains press releases of at least three activities, summaries of the week and work plans for the next week. But I found that as head of the team, I had more authority to push forward what I wanted to do, and I could take the phenomena I had previously observed in specific activities, put forward my own proposals, and pay for actions with the help of my teachers. For example, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on this really exciting fixed-point cooperation project between the college and the Green Health Care Group, which is going to be officially listed as a demonstration site in September 2019 – how great is that?! I&amp;rsquo;ve also been working with the College of Education to promote the &amp;lsquo;House of Love&amp;rsquo; activity, which is all about caring for children in the autistic school. I&amp;rsquo;ve also set up a daily volunteer contact group, and with the team&amp;rsquo;s support, we&amp;rsquo;ve encouraged at least 300 students to participate in the daily practice of public welfare. I&amp;rsquo;m currently thinking about how to make it sustainable after I leave the association.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End of A Chapter in Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/05/30/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/05/30/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All theory is gray, but the golden tree of life springs ever green.&amp;rdquo; I originally intended to borrow this line from Faust, feigning a sense of depth to mark the end of these four years. Yet at this moment, what floods my mind is not a series of adjectives but vivid memories of events and specific people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My parents, who have stood unwaveringly behind me since the day I was born, have been my greatest support. My advisor PENG, whose thoughtful guidance helped me realize my passion for theory far outweighs my interest in industry work, gave my life plan a new direction. And all the friends I have met along the way. Together, we ran through campuses and cities, dedicating ourselves to public service. We insisted on pursuing in-depth reporting and even founded our own magazine. We spent countless hours practicing in the taekwondo gym and the dance studio, and we honed our communication skills through student leadership roles. These experiences enriched my college years beyond measure and helped me discover a part of myself, someone who cherishes solitude more than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Savoring Beijing: My Top Food Highlights!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/01/09/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/01/09/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I saw the news, it suddenly reminded me of a year when I traveled to Beijing three times in three months to handle various documents. Of course, every trip to Beijing meant an opportunity to dive into its food scene. Here are my top three favorite dishes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shabu-shabu – absolutely unbeatable, my top pick!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pear soup – sweet but perfectly balanced, earning second place.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir-fried vegetables – from a restaurant famous for its roast duck, a solid third.&#xA;While Beijing’s food is incredible, I can’t help but miss Cantonese cuisine. I’m longing for those familiar flavors and hoping this chapter ends soon. We all deserve carefree and joyful days again!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Beijing%20food-01.jpg&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Beijing Food Map 1, including shabu-shabu, roast duck, lo mein, small hanging pear soup, fried noodles, bean curd dumplings, rice noodles, fried eggs, cold skin&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Beijing%20food-02.jpg&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Beijing Food Map 2, including fried hechibanko, dan dan noodles, wontons, grilled cold noodles, boiled language, Japanese restaurants in hutongs and Osaka cuisine in Liangmaqiao&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
