<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Daily Life on Zhenting HE</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/my-daily-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Daily Life on Zhenting HE</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 15:20:57 -1800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/my-daily-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The First Snow of 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/11/21/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 15:20:57 -1800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/11/21/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/videos/2024%20first%20snow%20video.mp4&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;The First Snow Moment of the year!&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I saw the first snowfall of the year, and this morning it seemed to materialize as  “sunrise in the east and snow in the west”. I was reminded of the original poem, “The west is veiled in the rain, the east enjoys sunshine.My gallant is as deep in love as the day is fine. （东边日出西边雨，道是无情却有情”）” It’s from a poem called “Two Songs of the Bamboo Branch（《竹枝词二首》）” by Liu Yuxi, who was a poet during the Tang Dynasty. The poem says that while the sun is rising in the east, it is raining in the west. It also says that the sky is not clear but there is clear sunshine. The poem talks about the weather, but the author uses a clever pun, “sunny - love,” to write about both weather and love. The sun is shining in the east and raining in the west, so I thought he was heartless, but he still has love.&#xA;Kind of like my current situation and state of mind.&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2024%20first%20snow-01.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Window before and after the first snow&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2024%20first%20snow-02.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;The Other Side of Clear&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;Actually, the “sun snow” phenomenon is pretty straightforward. It happens when cold and warm air masses converge locally. When the cold air hits the warm air underneath, the dry cold air and warm moist air meet and form snowfall. At the same time, the clouds at the top aren&amp;rsquo;t thick enough to block the sun completely. There might be some sunlight coming through the gaps in the clouds, which will make it look like there&amp;rsquo;s sunshine and snow on the ground at the same time. Since there aren&amp;rsquo;t many clouds, “solar snow” doesn’t stick around for long. It usually happens in the 9-10 or 15-16 hour window. You don&amp;rsquo;t need fancy weather to get a short burst of snow. It&amp;rsquo;s more about enjoying the view than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Youth Volunteer Association Yearly Memories </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/07/05/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/07/05/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I just happened to be working on the summary of the Youth Volunteer Association 2019, so I just happened to dump a copy of the English version on my website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a part of the Youth Volunteer Association for a year and a half now, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been leading activities almost every Saturday morning and afternoon. It&amp;rsquo;s been a year of growth and development for me, moving from volunteering to leading a team. When I first took over, I always felt that going to specific volunteer positions and helping specific people seemed more effective than taking on more managerial positions such as liaising and coordinating, especially for us students. I have to admit that I&amp;rsquo;m not that into spending time on these things, to be honest. I really enjoy reporting and coordinating all kinds of meetings, and reporting the progress of my work to the college and the school league committee every week. This report contains press releases of at least three activities, summaries of the week and work plans for the next week. But I found that as head of the team, I had more authority to push forward what I wanted to do, and I could take the phenomena I had previously observed in specific activities, put forward my own proposals, and pay for actions with the help of my teachers. For example, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on this really exciting fixed-point cooperation project between the college and the Green Health Care Group, which is going to be officially listed as a demonstration site in September 2019 – how great is that?! I&amp;rsquo;ve also been working with the College of Education to promote the &amp;lsquo;House of Love&amp;rsquo; activity, which is all about caring for children in the autistic school. I&amp;rsquo;ve also set up a daily volunteer contact group, and with the team&amp;rsquo;s support, we&amp;rsquo;ve encouraged at least 300 students to participate in the daily practice of public welfare. I&amp;rsquo;m currently thinking about how to make it sustainable after I leave the association.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
