<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Exhibition Record on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/my-exhibition-record/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Exhibition Record on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/my-exhibition-record/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Volunteer Experience|Caring for Women and Children in Urban Villages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/04/23/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/04/23/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What makes Shenzhen truly special to me is the warmth and resilience of its people. This spirit inspired me to become part of the Green Rose Volunteer Community, where we work to uplift women and children in urban villages. Every Friday night, I host film screenings for local kids, sharing stories that spark curiosity and encourage growth. Watching the community evolve week by week, I see Shenzhen’s legacy come alive through the small, sustainable changes we create together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Exhibition|The World&#39;s First Cologne &amp; Perfume Museum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/11/23/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/11/23/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I think of the city of Cologne, the first thing that comes to mind is Cologne Cathedral. But when I came to Cologne and learned about its history, I realised that the church hadn&amp;rsquo;t even been built when Farina was founded 300 years ago. Cologne Cathedral was not officially completed until 1880, but the city had become famous for its cologne, Oudtclum, long before that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1708, at the age of 23, Farina left her home in northern Italy and travelled north along the Rhine to Cologne. At the time, the city was attracting many people with its prosperity and reputation as the &amp;lsquo;Rome of the North&amp;rsquo;. Farina joined her brother, who had been living in Cologne for many years, where she invented a unique perfume.&#xA;In a letter to her brother, Farina described her work: &amp;ldquo;I have invented a perfume that takes you back to the rainy spring mornings of Italy. The blend of citrus, lemon, grapefruit and Italian flowers was fresh and delightful, and in 1709 the brothers officially founded the company, calling the perfume &amp;lsquo;Eau de Cologne&amp;rsquo;, meaning &amp;lsquo;water from Cologne&amp;rsquo;. Eau de Cologne&amp;rsquo;, meaning &amp;lsquo;water from Cologne&amp;rsquo;. This perfume became the origin of &amp;lsquo;cologne&amp;rsquo;. Yesterday I went to the address of the 300-year-old company, which is still open.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Exhibition|Revisiting Duchamp&#39;s &#39;Fountain&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/08/09/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/08/09/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Encountering Marcel Duchamp&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Fountain&amp;rsquo;at the Philadelphia Museum of Art was an unexpected but delightful surprise. Although I had long been aware of its pivotal role in the history of modern art, standing in front of the piece in person offered a profoundly different experience. This deceptively simple work, a porcelain urinal turned upside down, transcends its form to pose provocative questions: What defines art? Where are its boundaries?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Fountain.jpg&#34; width=&#34;360&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;&amp;#39;Fountain&amp;#39;, Note: The fountain in the collection of the Philadelphia Museum of Art is one of the earliest of 14 reproductions as large as the original. The signature, &amp;#39;R. Mutt 1917&amp;#39; was added by Duchamp himself in 1950.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a child, I first heard about &amp;lsquo;Fountain&amp;rsquo;through an art book, and its reputation left me puzzled. How could an ordinary urinal be considered art? It lacked the intricate craftsmanship or grandeur often associated with masterpieces in museums. More than a decade later, seeing the 1950 replica in person revived my childhood confusion, but also brought new insight. Duchamp&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Fountain&amp;rsquo;asserts that art lies not only in technical skill or aesthetic appeal, but in the artist&amp;rsquo;s power to give objects new meaning. As Timothy Rub, CEO of the Philadelphia Museum of Art, aptly observed, &amp;ldquo;A hundred years ago, &amp;lsquo;Fountain&amp;rsquo;shook the art world to its core. Artists and critics debated whether it was a masterpiece or a prank. By calling a ceramic urinal a &amp;lsquo;readymade&amp;rsquo;, Duchamp fundamentally changed the course of modern art. Today, young artists are still inspired or enraged by it. This enduring relevance underlines the importance of revisiting the piece and reflecting on its meaning a century later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Exhibition|Record of Paintings Seen at the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/08/07/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023/08/07/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While sorting out my memories, I found out that the Boston Museum of Fine Arts has a description of the paintings, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to put some records of the paintings on the website and post a link to them. If you are interested in this content, you can click &lt;a href=&#39;https://collections.mfa.org/advancedsearch;jsessionid=7789F17F27257FC632ACCAEA86A506B0/&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;here&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a &gt; to go to the official website of the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston. This will also make it easier for me to recall later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Exhibition|My Zodiac Sculpture at the Metropolitan Museum of Art</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/11/25/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2022/11/25/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My zodiac sign is the dragon (Loong/Dragon), and when I saw these works at the Met, I immediately thought about the stark contrast between the representation of this zodiac sign in Chinese and Western contexts. The differing understandings and symbolism of the dragon between China and the West reflect the diverse interpretations of nature, social order, and morality in each culture.&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/MMA/1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;Carvings of Dragon&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;In Chinese culture, the dragon is seen as a symbol of honor, good fortune, and authority, carrying profound cultural and spiritual connotations. It represents the harmony between heaven and earth, the legitimacy of imperial power, and the power of nature. The image of the Chinese dragon often conveys love, shelter, strength, and wisdom. For instance, the dragon is frequently found on imperial symbols, such as the emperor’s robe or jade seal, symbolizing a strong connection between the ruler and the deities of heaven and earth. Its esteemed status and harmonious relationship with the natural world reflect a deep respect for cosmic order and social stability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
